Patent Office, Ministry of Economy
I'm Mika Shimotsuki
from Criminal Investigation Department Division 1
公安局刑事課一係所属　霜月美佳
at the MWPSB.
I'm requesting
permission to enter
経済省特許局記録保管室への立ち入りを申請します
the Ministry of Economy
Patent Office's archive room.
Archive Room
Patents owned
by the Togane Foundation...
東金財団の所有特許…
Kirito Kamui
Kirito Kamui's treatment records
One record found
あった
There it is.
1. How to create a composite body
for multi-body transplant and live organ transplant
2. Transplant rejection immune evasion medicine
3. Decellularization method and artificial tissue
for implantation into human body
4. Transplant materials and how to create them
The technology patent applications
filed based on Kirito Kamui's surgery...
鹿矛囲桐斗の手術によって　申請された技術特許
How to create a composite body
for multi-body transplant and live organ transplant
A surgery to join pieces of 184 bodies creating a composite body
Multi-body transplant...
A surgery to join pieces of 184 bodies...!
多体移植…
１８４名の遺体を使った結合手術
飛行機事故の犠牲者
The plane crash victims...
彼らの遺体は切り刻まれ　一人の少年へと移植された
Their bodies were cut into pieces
and got implanted into a boy.
So that was Kamui, huh?
それが鹿矛囲か
He said that he has 184 people's
bodies and personalities
彼は言っていた
７人の脳を含む　１８４人の肉体と人格的存在
including seven people's brains...
...and that that's who he is.
それが　自分という人間だと
I'm surprised to know that
multi-body brain transplant is possible.
脳の多体移植なんてことが可能だとは驚きだな
To be honest, the chance of success
for this surgery was pretty much zero.
正直言って　成功する見込みは　ほとんどない手術だった
If I was asked to do it again,
I probably couldn't.
もう一度　同じことをやれと言われても　無理だろう
However...
しかし…　彼は生きた
...he has lived as an existence
whose Psycho-Pass cannot be measured at all.
サイコパスを　一切測定されない存在となって
Right... to machines,
he's nothing but a jumble of corpses.
そう
彼は機械の認識上は　つなぎ合わされた死体にすぎない
So that's Kirito Kamui...
それが鹿矛囲桐斗…
奪われ続けるなら
If I keep having things taken away from me, I'm gonna lose my mind
Ubaware tsuzukeru nara mou kurutte shimau yo
奪われ続けるなら
もう狂ってしまうよ
This endless "end" will make me stop breathing
Owari no nai "owari" ni boku wa iki wo shinaku natte
終わりの無い「終わり」に僕は息をしなくなって
Enigmatic Feeling
Enigmatic feeling
Why do they have to take things away from me? I'm about to fall apart
Ubawanakya ikenai no? Mou hodokete shimau yo
奪わなきゃいけないの
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
The world began to melt
Sekai ga tokedashite
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
God descended to confront and ask me
Kami-sama ga orite kite boku ni tsukitsuketa
神様が降りて来て
僕に突きつけた
"Who are you?"
Who are you?
I freed myself by walking in the divide of this world broken into two
Futatsu ni wakareta sekai ni sotte jibun wo hanatta
２つに分かれた世界に沿って
自分を放った
Is there only one God in such a fine borderline?
Kamihitoe darou kamihitoe darou kyoukaisen kami wa hitori na no?
紙一重だろう　紙一重だろう
境界線　神は１人なの
I'm gonna lose my mind, I'm gonna lose my mind...
Okashiku natte okashiku natte
おかしくなって おかしくなって
Suddenly I'll find myself taking you away
Fui ni kimi wo ubatte shimau no darou
ふいに君を奪ってしまうのだろう
Crazy! Crazy!
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
Because my heart can't focus
Pinto no awanai kokoro ni
ピントの合わない心に
Shake me! Shake me!
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I can't even look into the mirror
Kagami sae mo nozokenai
鏡さえも覗けない
When the surgery was finished,
オペが終わった時点では
he was still a normal human
that scanners were able to recognize.
まだ　彼はスキャナに認識される　普通の人間だった
#8: Conception of the Sibyl <AA
He told me that
he realized his uniqueness
彼が自分の特異性を　自覚したのは
when he became able
to live a normal daily life.
日常生活が送れるようになってからだそうだ
The more engrafted
the implanted parts became,
移植した部位が生着していけばいくほど
the less often he was
recognized by scanners.
スキャナに認識される頻度が　…減っていった
Time went by and soon I became
a ghost who was cut off from society.
そうして　時間がたち
やがて　僕は社会から切り離された　透明人間となった
At first, I did try
to get recognized.
初めのうちは努力もした
There were times when
I purposely committed crimes
わざと　人目に付く犯罪を起こし
that attracted public attention
and hoped to be judged.
裁かれるのを期待したこともあった
I also consulted people I thought I could trust,
including doctors and counselors.
医者や　カウンセラーをはじめ信頼できそうな人間に相談もした
But when they saw my uniqueness
with their own eyes, they walked away.
だが　僕の特異性を目の当たりにすると
皆　離れていった
I can imagine. Acknowledging someone
who isn't recognized by Sibyl
だろうな
シビュラに認識されない人間なんてもんを肯定することは
is the same as doubting
the foundation of this society.
今の社会に疑いを持つことに等しい
僕はシビュラだけでなく
Sibyl wasn't the only one.
My existence was denied
by everyone who was dependent on it.
それにすがる　全ての人間から　存在を否定された
Why I can't be acknowledged
by anyone and have to disappear...
なぜ自分は誰にも認められず　消えねばならないのか
I searched for the reason
and soon came across...
僕は理由を探し　やがてたどりついた
...the Season of Hell.
地獄の季節に
I knew you'd know about it.
さすが　ご存じのようで
I've only heard of it.
聞いたことくらいはある　その程度だ
At one time, the Ministry of Economy
proposed a support system for citizens
かつて　シビュラシステムに代わる国民支援制度が
to replace the Sibyl System,
and it became controversial.
経済省から発案され　議論を呼んだ
The system was called Panopticon.
It would control the traffic and banks
それは交通と銀行を管制し　その全てを把握する
and keep an eye
on all of them.
「パノプティコン」と呼ばれるシステムだった
Panopticon is the name
of a system
パノプティコン　かつてジェレミー・ベンサムが
that allows one to monitor
everything from one place.
収容所の建築形態として構築した
It's an architectural form designed
as a detention facility by Jeremy Bentham.
全事象展望監視システムの名称だ
By monitoring and recording
people's actions and economic activities,
市民の行動と経済活動を監視　記録することで
it'd prevent crimes
before they happened
犯罪を未然に防ぎ　最適な生き方を導く
and guide citizens towards
the best way of living.
It was quite a simple proposal,
but you could call it ideal as well.
至極単純ではあるが　理想的な提案ともいえる
Ideal, huh?
理想的か
To citizens, whose
every move is monitored,
全てを監視される市民にとっちゃ　まさしく監獄だ
that is the very
definition of a prison.
And how exactly is that different
from the current society?
今の社会とどう違うと？
Let's go back to what
we were talking about.
話を戻そう
They started to do test deployments
of Panopticon for traffic monitoring.
交通分野で試験的に運用されるようになったパノプティコンに
But did you know it started having
a great deal of problems at some point?
ある時期から多大な不具合が発生し始めたことはご存じでしょうか？
Yeah, because of that,
the adoption of Panopticon was shelved.
それが原因となり　パノプティコンの採用は見送られた
Right. Thus, Sibyl's rule
has continued until today.
そう　そうしてシビュラによる統治は今に至るまで続くこととなった
But, what if someone had
intended for that to happen...?
もし　それが何者かにより導かれた結論で
What if everything was arranged
in order to ensure that result?
それを得るために　全てが仕組まれていたとしたら…
That's a conspiracy theory that was
widespread around that time, too.
そいつは　当時も散々流れた陰謀論だ
A conspiracy theory?
Don't make me laugh.
何が陰謀論なものか…
Interfering with
the Ministry of Economy,
経済省への横やりや　人材の操作と流出
the manipulation and draining
of valuable human resources,
the scramble for a budget,
the dealings amongst politicians...
予算の奪い合い　政治家同士の取引
Those things really did happen.
それらは実際に起こったことだ
In fact, as a result...
事実　その結果として…
The number of plane crashes
and traffic accidents around that time
その周辺時期の航空　および交通事故は
were dozens of times higher
than in a typical year.
例年の数十倍にも跳ね上がった
A large number of people
were victimized during that time.
多大な犠牲者を出した　その期間を
Later on, people named
that period of time the Season of Hell.
後に　地獄の季節と称した
So you found
your answer there.
君はそこに　答えを見いだしたわけか
I came to learn about everything
and discovered what I needed to do...
全てを知り　自分の成すべきことを見いだした僕は
Then I became
a present-day medicine man.
現代のメディスンマンとして目覚めた
It was about five years ago
that I was reunited with him.
その彼との再会は　今から５年ほど前だった
I was dependent on drugs
around that time due to excessive stress.
当時の私は　ストレス過多による薬漬けでね
The cause was simple.
原因は何でもない
My mind couldn't endure
the heavy responsibility of a doctor.
私の精神が医者という重責に　耐えられなかった
It's the same old boring story
that happens all the time.
そんなどこにでもある　つまらないものだ
Kamui healed me.
鹿矛囲は私を癒やしてくれた
He had obtained the medical data
that we were forbidden to see
彼は私たちが知ることを禁じられた医療データを手に入れ
and acquired the skills
to clear people's Psycho-Pass
正しい瞑想と薬物投与で
by teaching them how to meditate
and giving them appropriate medication.
人のサイコパスをクリアにするすべを身に付けていたんだ
Skills that can make the Psycho-Pass
of any criminal clear, huh?
どんな犯罪者のサイコパスもクリアにできる技術か…
That alone can be
revenge toward his past.
それ自体が　過去への復讐になり得るな
It won't end up
as simple revenge.
単なる復讐にとどまらない
Kamui will overturn
everything for us.
鹿矛囲なら全てを覆してくれる
He's someone who enables us
to dream like that.
そんな夢を見させてくれるような男なんだよ　彼は
全てを覆す　それが鹿矛囲の目的
Overturn everything...
That's Kamui's goal...
I see... So that's what it's about.
そういうこと
It's not just me
you want to judge,
裁きたいのは私だけでなく
but the entire
Sibyl System, huh, Kirito?
シビュラシステム全体というわけね　桐斗君
A human created by joining pieces
of corpses together...?
死体をつなぎ合わせて　つくられた人間なんて…
気持ち悪い…
How creepy...
The last access to the file
was only two months ago.
ファイルの閲覧記録　前回がつい２カ月前になってる
Mika Shimotsuki
Shunji Uchikoga
Who's this?
誰？
There he is!
He's one of Kamui's Holos.
いた　鹿矛囲のホロの一人
So Kamui came here?
鹿矛囲がここに来た
霜月監視官は？
Where's Inspector Shimotsuki?
She contacted me and said that
she'd continue to check medical institutions.
引き続き　医療機関を当たってみると連絡を受けました
I understand.
If that's the case,
分かりました
そういうことなら　まずは今いるメンバーで現状報告を
why don't we go ahead
and start giving our status reports?
Well then, I'll go first.
では　私から
I searched for people who share
the same names as the accident victims.
事故被害者と　同姓同名の人物を探してみたところ
都心部だけで　５４人が該当しました
That search resulted in fifty-four matches
just within the inner-city area.
Those fifty-four people...
その５４人は…
No, it's probably safe to say that all
the 184 people, the victims except Kamui,
いいえ　鹿矛囲本人を除く事故被害者１８４人分の外見は
are the Holos that he wears.
全て彼のまとうホロとみて間違いないでしょう
Yes. That therapist who provided
his service in the MWPSB...
はい　公安に出入りしていたセラピストも
That pharmacist
at the mental care facility...
メンタルケア施設にいた薬剤師も
...as well as the hostage
in the first incident...
最初の事件の人質女性も…
It means they were all Kamui.
全て　鹿矛囲だったということ
B-But it might also mean that
h-he uses only the Holos of those victims.
で…でも　鹿矛囲は事故の被害者のホロしかつ…使わないのかも…
Yes, I agree.
ええ　私もそう思う
Kamui is obsessed
with the accident
鹿矛囲は事故と　それにより植え付けられた１８４人に固執している
and those 184 people who were
implanted in him because of it.
In that sense, we can say
that his face has been revealed.
その意味で　鹿矛囲の顔は割れたと言っていい
Mr. Ginoza, how did
your investigation go?
宜野座さんの方は？
From the organs left
at Kamui's hideout,
鹿矛囲の隠れ家に残された臓器から
we determined the people
who were possibly swapped.
入れ替わりの可能性がある人物を割り出した
Every single one of them is a big shot
from every sector of society.
揃いも揃って　各界の大物ばかりだ
It was Dr. Masuzaki who had
replaced those influential people
社会への影響力が強い人物を　別人にすり替えていたのは
with someone else.
枡嵜医師です
He admitted it himself.
本人も認めています
He killed them while
pretending to treat them.
治療と見せ掛けて　殺していた
To think that he kept his Psycho-Pass clear
while performing such terrible acts.
それだけのことを繰り返しながら　サイコパスをクリアに保てるとは…
That is the uniqueness Kamui has.
それが鹿矛囲の特異性
With his compounding
of drugs and counseling,
薬物調合とカウンセリングで
he can even clear the Psycho-Pass
of serious latent criminals...
重篤な潜在犯でさえ　サイコパスをクリアにしてしまえる
...to the level that it could be
called brainwashing.
洗脳と言っていいレベルで
Medical care is his most powerful weapon, huh?
How troublesome...
医療こそが最大の武器か　厄介だな
At the same time, he's limited
his attacks to medical institutions.
同時に　彼の攻撃対象は医療関係に限定されている
Remember the claim of responsibility
made by Kitazawa the bomber?
覚えていますか　爆弾犯の喜汰沢の犯行声明
H-He said he targeted
a pharmaceutical company.
い…医薬品会社を狙ったって　言ってた
And the barricade incident
happened in a mental care facility.
そして　立てこもりが起きた現場はメンタル医療施設だった
The strange thing is that
he used the port as his hideout.
妙なのは　港を隠れ家にしていた点ですね
There must've been
some advantage.
何かメリットがあったはず
The advantage of using a port...
港のメリット…
Ms. Kunizuka, have there been
any unsolved missing persons cases
六合塚さん　この数カ月で
未解決の行方不明事件はありますか？
in the past few months?
I don't think there's
anything in the record.
記録にはないと思いますが…
That's strange since
some people must've gone missing.
それ　変　人　減ってないと　おかしいのに…
そうね　内臓を抜き取られて殺された人がいるなら
I agree. If there are people
who were killed with their organs removed,
those people who were going to have
the organs implanted had to disappear.
移植される前の人物は消えていないと　おかしい
True. People whose disappearances
aren't recognized by society...
確かに　消えたことが認識されない人物となると…
Wait.
待てよ
If I remember right,
I saw foreign newspapers and currencies left there.
確か　現場に国外の新聞や紙幣が残されていたな
I see, illegal aliens...
そうか　密入国者
So the impersonators
are illegal aliens?
成り済ましているのは　密入国者ということですか？
That's a possibility.
その可能性があります
What is he trying to achieve
by going that far?
そうまでして　何をする気なんだ？
What do you want?
何の用だ？
Can you afford to be
loitering around here?
こんな所で　油売ってていいのか？
It's not that I came to see you because
I had too much free time on my hands.
暇を持て余して　会いに来たわけじゃありません
I've been interested
in you for a while.
以前から　あなたには興味がありました
Jouji Saiga, a lecturer
who colored his students black...
受講生を黒く染めた講師　雑賀譲二
I'm not thrilled to hear that.
うれしくないね
The ability to control
the Psycho-Pass of others...
他者のサイコパスを操る能力
Something like that
can't be a simple skill.
そんなものが　ただの技術であるはずがありません
Indeed. If something like that could be
passed down, this society wouldn't hold.
確かに　そんなものが　伝達できるなら
この社会は成り立たなくなっちまうからな
If it's not a skill,
it's a talent.
技術でないなら　それは才能です
You have a talent for clouding
a person's Psycho-Pass,
人をクリアにする　鹿矛囲とは真逆の
which is the exact opposite
of Kamui's talent for clearing it.
サイコパスを濁らせる才能を　あなたは持っている
You want me to say
"I'm honored" or something?
光栄だ　…とでも言えばいいのか？
そしてそれ故に　どんなに自分が干渉しても
And because of that,
you're dependent on Inspector Tsunemori,
whose Psycho-Pass doesn't change
no matter how much you get involved.
サイコパスが変化しない　常守監視官に依存している
Oh...?
Excuse me.
失礼
Understood.
了解です
Being dependent, huh?
Then what about you?
依存か　なら　お前は　どうなんだ？
You're... too sharp.
あなたはキレ過ぎる
The data Kamui accessed is heavily
focused on drug related categories.
鹿矛囲の閲覧したデータは薬品関連の項目に偏っている
Among them was the manufacturing technologies
for the new LACOUSE,
その中には第一の事件で喜汰沢が爆弾を仕掛けた
LACOUSE
新型ラクーゼの精製技術
which is related
to Kitazawa's bombing incident.
There is also an access record
for several drugs
そして　立てこもり事件の起こったメンタルケア施設で扱っていた
used at the mental care facility
where the barricade incident happened.
数種類の薬品の閲覧履歴も残されていた
The one related to all these is...
いずれも背後にいるのは…
Patent Owner: The Togane Foundation
鹿矛囲は東金財団に復讐しようとしている？
Kamui is trying to get revenge
against the Togane Foundation?
航空機事故の手術で
Their patented technologies
were used
東金財団が保有していた特許技術が使用されている
in the surgery performed
because of the plane crash.
脳を生きたまま　摘出する技術
A technology for extracting
a brain while one is still alive...
A technology to have extracted
brains joined together...?
摘出した脳を　つなぎ合わせる技術…
Why did they own
technologies like these?
なぜ　こんな技術を　保有していたの？
What's in the related categories?
関連項目は…
ドローンによる　全自動での脳の摘出
Fully automated brain
extraction by a Drone...
Suggestions of surgeries
that don't require humans...
人間を必要としない　手術の提案
What on earth are these?
何これ…
特許出願者の名前
The name of the patent applicant is...
Misako Togane
東金美沙子
...Misako Togane.
東金朔夜の母親
Sakuya Togane's mother...
Chairperson, The Togane Foundation
Applicant Information
Birth Date: February 19, 2034 (died in 2109)
Current Address: 268 Ichiban-cho, Chiyoda Ward, Tokyo
５年前に死んでいる
She died five years ago.
父親は？
What about his father?
This information is sealed
The information is sealed?
封印措置？
Does it mean that patent technologies
have something to do with his birth, too?
あいつの出生にも　特許技術が　絡んでるってこと？
Proof of the congenitalness of 'AA',
an idiosyncrasy related to Psycho-Pass
One record found
特異体質「ＡＡ」の先天性実証例
Proof of the congenitalness of "AA,"
an idiosyncrasy...
This information is sealed
No...
駄目…
私のサイコパスが濁っちゃう
My Psycho-Pass
is gonna get clouded.
What should I do?
どうしたら…
Oh yeah.
そうか…　そうだ
That's right!
It fell through.
不発でしたね
Yeah.
ええ　すり替えられた人間をしらみつぶしに当たるつもりだったけど…
I was going to check
those impersonators one by one, but...
仕方がないとはいえ　後手後手ですね
There's nothing we could have done,
but still, we're always a step behind.
An alarm?
What's going on?
アラーム？　何が…
The weight sensor I had set up
on the floor in my apartment went off.
自宅の床の加重センサーが反応した
やはり自分をおとりに使っていたのか
So you were using yourself as a decoy after all.
You're unbelievable.
あきれた人だ
Sorry, I'll listen
to your complaints later.
ごめん　苦情は後で聞くから
I-I came to check the fire prevention
and waterworks system.
ぼ…防火と水道システムの　点検に参りました
Since you're busy,
I thought you signed the paper
お忙しいとのことで　管理用の鍵の使用許可にサインを頂いてるはずですが…
to permit us to use
the management key.
I'm surprised to see
you left this thing as is.
驚きですよ　まだ残してあるなんて
Well, there's no harm, so...
まあ　害はありませんから
In order to put yourself
in Kamui's state of mind,
鹿矛囲の心理と重なるには
やつの見た景色を保持しておくのが一番
it's best to preserve
the view he saw.
Did I guess right?
図星ですか
さすがですね
I'd expect no less from you.
I'm impressed.
You are a born detective.
感服しますよ　あなたは生まれながらのデカだ
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
かわいげが足りないという意味です
It means, you lack charm.
公安局から通知…
A notification from the MWPSB...?
Grandma?
おばあちゃん？
自宅の警報を感知
The alarm at your home
has been triggered.
The security level for Aoi Tsunemori,
protective custody subject,
保護対象常守葵の警備レベルをＢに変更しました
has been changed to Level B.
Oh, that's... uhm...
それ…　えっと
Grandmother, huh...
祖母か…
事件の発端は１５年前の航空機事故にさかのぼる
It all started with a plane crash
fifteen years ago.
It was a tragic accident
where 184 children were included
死亡した２０１名の乗員乗客のうち
１８４名が児童という悲惨な事故を利用して
among the 201 passengers
and crew who died.
And, someone gained a great deal
by taking advantage of this accident.
莫大な利益を享受した者たちがいた
それが　東金財団
The Togane Foundation.
そして　このときの唯一の生き残りが
And the only one who survived
this accident was Kirito Kamui.
The only one who survived
鹿矛囲桐斗である
当時財団を仕切っていた東金美沙子は
Misako Togane, the one who was
running the Foundation at the time,
was devoted to research
on an idiosyncrasy called "AA."
「ＡＡ」という特異体質の研究に執心しており
As part of her research, there was
an experiment used to demonstrate
その実証実験の一つが
脳を摘出し　つなぎ合わせるという
the use of a patented technology
owned by the Foundation,
財団が持つ特許技術を最新の環境で試すことだった
in which they extracted brains
and had them joined together.
She pushed her research forward
彼女は鹿矛囲や事故犠牲者たちの遺体を使い
by using Kamui
and the accident victims' dead bodies.
自らの研究を推し進め
As a result, the Foundation's
patented technology evolved further.
結果　財団が持つ特許技術は　さらなる進化を遂げた
Kirito Kamui's goal in his crimes
is to retaliate against the Togane Foundation.
鹿矛囲桐斗の犯行目的は
Kirito Kamui's goal in his crimes
is to retaliate against the Togane Foundation.
そうした東金財団への報復である
財団をマークすることで　鹿矛囲逮捕に近づける
We can get closer to the arrest of Kamui
by keeping an eye on the Foundation.
しかし現在の一係は重大な問題を抱えている
However, Division 1 is currently
burdened with a significant problem.
That is, Akane Tsunemori
and Sakuya Togane.
それは　常守朱と東金朔夜の存在だ
東金朔夜は「ＡＡ」を人工的につくりだそうとした
Sakuya Togane was created
from an experiment by Misako Togane
who was trying
to artificially create "AA."
東金美沙子の実験によって生み出された
It can be speculated that this caused him
to hold the worst Crime Coefficient.
それが史上最悪の犯罪係数を持つに至った経緯と推測される
In other words, it means that Kamui,
the ringleader of this crime,
つまり　事件の首謀者である鹿矛囲と東金朔夜は
Kamui, the ringleader of this crime,
and Sakuya Togane are connected by the key word 'AA.'
and Sakuya Togane
are connected by the key word "AA."
「ＡＡ」というキーワードで　つながっていることになる
鹿矛囲桐斗と東金朔夜は等しく危険である
Kirito Kamui and Sakuya Togane
are equally dangerous.
東金朔夜は他人の犯罪係数を上げることに喜びを覚える異常者だ
Sakuya Togane is a deviant
who takes pleasure
in raising others'
Crime Coefficients.
In fact, examples show that
現に　今まで彼の担当となった監視官５名全員が
all the five Inspectors he worked with
in the past became latent criminals.
潜在犯化しているという　実例がある
It is anticipated that
Inspector Tsunemori's Crime Coefficient
東金朔夜の影響により　常守監視官も近い将来
will also increase with Sakuya Togane's
influence in the near future.
犯罪係数が上がると　予想される
However, Inspector Tsunemori
does not seem to care about it
しかし　常守監視官本人は…
意にも介さず　忠告も受け入れようとしない
and shows no intention
of accepting the advice of others.
Inspector Tsunemori does not seem to care about it.
This is a serious situation.
これは　由々しき事態だ
Many Inspectors and Enforcers
have already become victims
常守監視官は　すでに　己の判断ミスにより
because of bad decisions
made by Inspector Tsunemori.
多数の監視官　および執行官を犠牲にしている
As it stands, not only can we not
arrest Kamui or remove Sakuya Togane,
このままでは　鹿矛囲の逮捕や　東金朔夜の排除はおろか
Not only can we not arrest Kamui or remove Sakuya Togane,
but the MWPSB itself could face an existential risk.
but the MWPSB itself
could face an existential risk.
公安局存続の危機にも　つながりかねない
Hence, I strongly call
for the dismissal of Inspector Tsunemori
故に私は　常守監視官の更迭
もしくは　権利停止の必要性を　強く訴える
or the suspension
of her rights as an Inspector.
２１１４年１１月２７日　公安局刑事課一係所属
November 27th, 2114.
November 27th, 2114
Mika Shimotsuki, Criminal
Investigation Department Division 1, MWPSB
Mika Shimotsuki, Criminal Investigation
Department Division 1, MWPSB.
霜月美佳
I'm sure Chief Kasei
will understand.
禾生局長なら　きっと分かってくれるはず
進展はなし…　か
No progress, huh?
Right. We checked
all those impersonators' houses
はい　すり替えられた人物たちの自宅別宅は　全て当たりましたが
and their second houses,
but we found no trace of them at all.
誰一人痕跡をつかめませんでした
このタイミングでの失踪
Considering the timing,
it's hard to think that they just ran.
単なる逃亡とは考えられないな
私もそう思います
I agree. They started
taking actions towards their goal.
彼らは目的に向けて動き始めた
We have to do whatever
it takes to stop them.
何としても止めなければ
まるで相手の狙いを把握しているかのような物言いだな
You sound as if you know
what their goal is.
If we are to trust Masuzaki,
Kamui's goal is a revolution.
枡嵜を信じるなら　鹿矛囲の目的は革命だ
In order to overturn the society,
he judges the existence that embodies it.
社会を転覆するため　その社会を体現する存在を裁く
そんな存在は　一つしかない
There's only one such existence.
The Sibyl System...
シビュラシステム…
This is an interesting report.
興味深い内容だ
To see you reached this information
within such a short time...
短期間でこれにたどりつくとは　君の捜査能力は大したものだな
You have an amazing
investigative ability.
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
By the way, about this "AA,"
this is what's called "open-door data."
ところで　この「ＡＡ」だが
これは　オープンドア・データと　呼ばれるものだ
オープンドア・データ？
Open-door data?
重要機密を暴こうとする社会不適合者を
It's a trap to lure in and fully understand
those who are unfit for society
おびき寄せて把握するためのわな
and who will try
to expose top secrets.
And you completely fell for it.
君は　それに　まんまと引っ掛かった
"AA" stands for "a priori acquit."
「AA」すなわち「Apriori Acquit」
先天的な免罪体質についてシビュラの重大な秘密だ
It's about having a criminally
asymptomatic constitution by nature,
which is Sibyl's biggest secret.
Hm? Huh?
Now, how should I deal with the girl
who deviated from the investigation
さて　捜査から逸脱してこのようなデータの収集にいそしんだ
and devoted herself
to collecting data like this instead?
君の処理　どうすべきか
まだ　この程度の悪化でとどまっていられるとは…
To see this produced such a small
change in your Psycho-Pass...
何で…
Why...?!
彼女はまだ使えます
We can still make use of her.
私に　任せていただけませんか
Could you leave her to me... Mother?
母さん
"Mother"...?
母さん…？
Misako Togane
Applicant Information
Birth Date: February 19, 2034 (died in 2109)
Current Address: 268 Ichiban-cho, Chiyoda Ward, Tokyo
Can't be...
そんな…　だって…
Huh? But...
You can do as you please.
I can deal with her anytime.
好きにしていいわ　処分はいつでもできるし
やはり問題なのは…
After all, the problem is...
常守と鹿矛囲のことなら　心配ありません
If you're thinking of Tsunemori and Kamui,
no need to worry.
I'll bring them both down.
２人とも私が仕留めてみせます
母さんとシビュラを美しく清らかにするのが
It's my role to make you and Sibyl
beautiful and pure, Mother.
私の役目です
What? What are you
talking about?
何？　何の話をしてるの？
Stop it... I don't wanna hear anything!
I don't wanna see anything!
やめて…　聞きたくない　見たくない
わ…私…　私何も知りませんから…
I... I don't know anything!
I won't tell anyone...
I'll forget about everything!
誰にも　話しませんから…
全部　忘れるから…
賢明な判断ね
That's wise.
あなたは　やはり理想的な市民だわ
You really are an ideal citizen...
...so ideal that you're boring.
退屈なほどに
Her reaction... She might become
a good model case for the time
この反応
いずれシステムを公開するときのモデルケースになるかもしれません
when we eventually reveal
the system to the public.
Yeah, why don't we try, huh?
そうね　試してみましょうか
では…
Well then...
霜月監視官
Inspector Shimotsuki,
we'll tell you the secret of this world.
あなたに　世界の秘密を教えてあげる
All is calm, all is bright
All is calm All is bright
A whispering fallen angel
Sasayaku tenshi wa ochite
囁く天使は堕ちて
い…　や…
No...
嫌ぁぁーっ
No!
Gently devours you, body and soul
Yasashiku hamu wa anata no subete o
優しく食むわ　あなたの全てを
It's my guilty
You notice me
Kidzuku
気づく　目を見開いてる
With your eyes wide open,
Me o mihiraiteru
A faint blue as lifeless as concrete
Honoaoi konkuriito
仄青い混凝土
In a cold tone,
Tsumetaku watashi o
冷たく私を
Call my name and give me a kiss
And then hold me in the arms of the empty shell that is your body
Soshite dakishimete anata no inai sono karada de
そして抱きしめて
あなたのいないその体で
That soul that you've cast out
Hakidashita sono inochi wa
吐き出しその生命は
Has not yet completely vanished
Mada katachi o nokoshiteiru wa
まだ形を残しているわ　紅く
I glimpse a vivid red eternity
Akaku azayaka na eien ga miete
鮮やかな永遠が見えて
It starts singing right next to me
Tonari de sore wa utaidasu
隣でそれは歌いだすわ
What was I born for
Come on, love me
Nee watashi o aishite
ねえ　私を愛して
Because I won't let you go
Hanasanai kara
離さないから
Hello my name is
A world where humans' state of mind
and the tendency of their personalities can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed, these measured numbers used to judge people's souls
are commonly called 'Psycho-Pass.'
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations
that appear in the show are fictitious,
and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.